Chester Burbidge

Web chester.codes
Github chestercodes

Profile

A software professional who is constantly learning and improving. Experienced with designing, building and deploying IAAS, PAAS and serverless cloud solutions on AWS and Azure. I have experience running .NET services and websites in a Windows Server environment. Passionate about automation and everything as code. I have used technologies for infrastructure as code (terraform and cloud specific), configurement management (Chef mostly) and general scripting (Powershell, bash, python etc).

Experience

Scott Logic - Software Engineer

2017 - 2018 (11m)

- Designed and implemented ETL pipeline on Azure using Data Factory V2. Implemented data warehouse reporting solution using SQL Datawarehouse and PowerBI.
- Wrote AWS infrastructure code for data engineering project using Terraform. Deployed a wide range of resources such as Kinesis, EC2 VMs and ECS containers.
- Developed Api for automated download and analysis of github repositories using .Net Core running F# on ubuntu.
- Introduced SpecFlow into project to easy the development and provide living documentation of automated tests.
- Ran internal study group for advancing company knowledge on cloud computing.

Abide Financial - Software Engineer

2015 - 2017 (2y, 7m)

- Developed code to enrich and validate financial transaction data using C# and T-SQL.
- Implemented CI and deployment solutions for AWS resources including EC2 and Lambda. This required extensive use of Teamcity and Octopus deploy. Created nuget packages to promote 'best practices' in build and deployment automation.
- Wrote Powershell scripts for file archival and other Windows Server administration tasks. Automated configuration of log aggregation agents on production systems.
- Spread best practices in methods and technologies through organising department wide, weekly workshops.

FundsLibrary - Junior Developer

2014 - 2015 (ly)

Maintained the Fundslibrary website in an agile environment. Practiced modern software development practices including TDD, CI and SOLID practices. Backend development involved C#, ASP.NET MVC and SQL Server to create web services and sites. Client side development used typescript, LESS and libraries such as KnockoutJs and jQuery.

Toplevel Computing - *Graduate Developer*

2013 - 2014 (1y)

Maintained proprietary web development product and extended behaviour to customer specifications. Role involved writing specifications, designs and performing the implementation of code changes.

Skills

Back End - AKKA.NET, Apache Spark, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET WebForms, Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, AWS DynamoDB, AWS Kinesis, AWS Redshift, AWS SQS, AWS S3, C++, C#, Docker, .NET Framework, ES6 Promises, F#, javascript, LINQ, NUnit, python, RESTFul webservices, SQL Server Management Studio, T-SQL, Visual studio, VB.NET, XSLT, XML

Cloud Computing - Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Resource Manager, Azure HdInsights, AWS Cloudformation, AWS DynamoDB, AWS EC2, AWS ECR, AWS ECS, AWS Lambda, AWS Kinesis, AWS Opsworks, AWS Redshift, AWS SQS, AWS S3, Docker, Powershell, python, Terraform

Devops - Azure Resource Manager, AWS Cloudformation, AWS EC2, AWS ECR, AWS ECS, AWS Lambda, AWS Opsworks, bash scripting, Cake, Chef, Continuous integration, Docker, git, grunt, Octopus Deploy, Packer, Powershell, python, Terraform, Teamcity

Front End - Angular Js, Bootstrap, Apache Cordova (Phone Gap), CSS, D3, .NET Framework, ES6 Promises, F#, grunt, HTML, Ionic framework, jasmine, javascript, jQuery, KnockoutJs, LESS, Puppeteer, react.js, RESTFul webservices, Typescript, Visual studio

Other - Apache Cordova (Phone Gap), JIRA, LaTeX, Resharper, R, Source safe, TFS

Testing - C#, jasmine, javascript, karma, MoQ, NUnit, Puppeteer, python, Specflow

Education

The University of Exeter

2010 - 2012

Phd Physics: The electrical properties of cell

Degree Not Attained

membranes

The University of Exeter

2007 - 2010

BSc. (Hons.) Mathematics and Physics

2:1

Queen Mary's College

2005 - 2007

A Levels

Mathematics (A), Physics (B), Electronics (B), BTEC Music Practice (Distinction). AS Level: Further Mathematics AS (C)

Volunteering

Codeclub 2015 - 2016

After school club for primary school children. Taught scratch, HTML CSS and python.

Codeclub 2013 - 2014

After school club for primary school children. Taught scratch, HTML CSS and python.